- You ready to go? - Let me just finish this.
-你準備好要走了嗎？ -讓我先把這個完成
Hey, Ross. Check this out.
嘿，羅斯，瞧
Yeah, I can't do that.
我就是做不好
- What are you doing? - Have you seen this?
-你在做什麼呢？ -你有看過這個嗎？
It's our new alumni website for college.
這是我們大學校友會的新網站
You can post messages for people, let everyone know what you're up to.
你可以留言給大家 讓大家知道你的近況
Oh, great. A faster way to tell people that I'm unemployed and childless.
喔，太好了，一個更快速方式 去告訴大家，我失業又沒小孩
It's actually interesting to find out what people are doing.
知道大家在做什麼，真有趣
Remember Andrea Rich?
記得艾卓雅裡奇嗎？
That tall girl that wouldn't sleep with you?
不肯跟你上床的那個高個子女生嗎？
Well, her Internet company went under, and she lost an ear in a boating accident.
她的網路公司倒了 而且在一次划船意外中失去一隻耳朵
Bet she'd sleep with you now.
我敢說她現在一定會跟你上床了
No, I already e-mailed her.
才不，我已經email問過她了
Let me see what you wrote about yourself.
讓我看看你是怎麼寫自己的
"Doctor of paleontology, two kids."
「古生物學博士，有兩個小孩」
Wait a second. You split with Carol because you had different interests?
等等，你跟凱羅分開的原因 是因為興趣不同嗎？
I think you split with Carol because you had one very similar interest.
我認為你跟她分開的原因 就是因為有相同的興趣
I'm gonna finish this later, okay? Let me just grab my coat.
我等一下再寫好了 讓我拿一件外套
Okay!
好的
What, did you think you learned how to do it in the last two minutes?
怎樣？你認為你花了兩分鐘 就能學會嗎？
Maybe we finish this for him.
或許我們可以幫他完成
Also, I cloned a dinosaur in my lab.
同時，我在實驗室裡複製了一隻恐龍
She is now my girlfriend.
她現在是我的女朋友了
I don't care what society says, it's the best sex I've ever had.
我不在乎社會的眼光 這是我有過的最完美的性愛
- And send. - No, no.. You can't do that to him.
-然後，寄出 -不，你不可以這樣
- All right, let's go. - Dude!
-好了，我們走 -老兄！
I think you made it clear you can't be trusted with the ball inside the house.
我想你很清楚的證明了 讓你在室內抱著球是不行的
And send.
然後，寄出
The One With The Memorial Service
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Hey. How was basketball?
嘿，籃球好玩嗎？
It was fun. Right up until Chandler got a finger in the eye.
很好玩，一直玩到錢德的眼睛 被手指戳到
Oh, no! Who did that?
喔，天啊，是誰弄的？
Chandler. Yeah.
錢德自己
Hey!
嘿！
- Rach? - Yeah?
-瑞秋 -怎樣？
What's Huggsy doing in the crib with Emma?
哈吉為什麼在艾□的嬰兒車裡呢？
She was just crawling around and found him, so I just let her sleep with him.
她在到處爬的時候抓到他 所以我就讓她跟他一起睡
- That's all right, isn't it? - Of course. Yeah.
-沒關係吧？ -當然，沒關係
It's a stuffed animal, you know? It's for kids. Not for adults.
只是填充玩具，你知道的 是給小孩玩的，不是給大人的
I know that.
這點我知道
Joey, you're sure? I mean, I know how much you love him.
喬伊，你確定嗎？ 我知道你很愛他
Rachel, let's be clear on this, okay? I do not love Huggsy.
瑞秋，讓我們說清楚好嗎？ 我沒有愛哈吉
I like him a normal amount.
我只是以正常的程度喜歡他
All right. Well, Emma loves him.
好吧，但是艾□愛死他了
Yeah. Well, why wouldn't she? He's a wonderful person!
是啊，為何不呢？ 他是那麼地美好！
- Hi. - Hey, Phoebe. How you doing?
-嗨 -嘿，菲比，你還好嗎？
- You feeling better? - Breaking up sucks.
-你感覺好點了嗎？ -分手真是難受
- Oh, I really miss Mike. - Oh, I'm so sorry.
-喔，我真的好想麥克 -喔，真抱歉
I've tried everything to feel better. I even tried writing a song about it..
我已經試過所有療傷法了 我甚至還嘗試要寫首歌
but I can't think of anything that rhymes with:
但是我不想出任何可以配這個調的…
Oh, I so know how you feel.
喔，我知道你的感覺
Breaking up with Richard was the hardest thing I've ever done in my life.
跟李察分手是我一生中 最困難的事了
All right, fine, I'll put another dollar in the Richard jar.
好嘛，我會再放一塊錢到 「李察」罐子裡
Hey, Monica, I'm gonna need your help getting through this.
嘿，摩妮卡 我需要你幫忙我度過這段時期
You're saying you're not gonna need my help?
你是說你不需要我幫忙嗎？
No. When I get to the point where I'm ready..
不，當我準備好要聽…
to hear cruel, mocking jokes about Mike, I'm gonna come to you.
糗死的麥克笑話時，我會來找你的
Oh, good, because I've already thought of three. Four! I just thought of a fourth!
很好，因為我已經想出三個了 四個！ 我剛剛又想出第四個！
Okay. I mean, I know I did the right thing.
好了，我知道我的決定是正確的
Mike never wants to get married..
麥克永遠都不想要結婚
and I shouldn't be in a relationship that has no future.
而我也不應該經營一段沒有未來的感情
But pretty soon, I'm gonna miss him so much..
但是很快的，我會很想念他
I'm gonna want to see him again, and you have to stop me.
我會想再見到他 你一定要阻止我
Okay, you got it.
好的，沒問題
Unless.. Am I being too crazy about this?
除非… 我是不是想太多了呢？
All right, so there's no future. But that doesn't mean we still can't have fun.
好吧，就算沒有未來又如何 那不表示我們不能玩一玩阿
- You know what? Forget what I said. - Really?
-你知道嗎？忘了我剛剛說的 -真的嗎？
- All right, if that's what you want. - That was a test, and you just failed.
-好吧，如果你那樣想的話 -那是個測試，你沒過關
Damn it! Rookie mistake!
該死的！新手失誤！
I have sex with dinosaurs?
我跟恐龍做愛？
I believe I read that somewhere.
我確定我好像在哪看過耶
Not only is it not funny, it's physically impossible! Okay?
不只不好笑，而且根本不可能 好嗎？
Depending on the species, I'd have to have a 6-foot-long.. It's not funny!
由於物種不同，我必須要有六尺長的… 不好笑！
I respectfully disagree.
我真心表示無法苟同
I can't believe you put that on my alumni page.
不敢相信你會在 我的校友網頁上那樣寫
- Who cares? Nobody reads those. - You better hope not..
-誰在乎呢？有誰會去看啊 -你最好是希望沒有
because I just read what you put on your page.
因為我剛剛就看到 你網頁上的一些訊息
- I don't have a page. - Oh, I respectfully disagree!
-我沒有網頁 -喔，我真心表示無法苟同！
Huggsy?
哈吉？
Huggsy.
哈吉
I want my penguin.
我要我的企鵝
Look at you. All sweet and innocent, sleeping like an angel.
瞧瞧你，甜美又天真的樣子 睡得跟天使一樣
With Emma's chubby little hands wrapped around you.
還有艾□那只肥肥的小手抱住你
It's okay, Emma. You stay asleep.
沒關係，艾□，你繼續睡
Step away from the crib! I have a weapon!
不要靠近嬰兒床！我有武器！
It's okay! It's okay, Rach! It's me! Put down the scrunchie.
沒關係！沒關係，瑞秋 是我，把發卷放下來
- What are you doing? - Well, I heard Emma stirring..
-你在做什麼？ -喔，我聽到艾□的聲音
so I came in to make sure she could reach Huggsy.
所以我過來確定一下 讓她可以抓到哈吉
Oh, thanks. All right, well, now that I'm up, I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
謝謝，既然我已經醒了 我要去上廁所
Okay, there you go, sweetie.
好的，拿去，親愛的
This isn't over!
我們還沒完！
Wait a second. Why would Ross tell everyone in your class..
等等，為什麼羅斯 要跟你班上每個人說…
that you are "as gay as the day is long"?
你是「同志到不能再同志了」呢？
Because I told everyone he slept with dinosaurs.
因為我告訴大家說，他跟恐龍上床
Well, that's clearly a joke. This could easily be true.
那很明顯的是個笑話 但是這個很有可能是真的
Would you get that, please? People have been calling to congratulate me all day.
拜託你去接好嗎？ 我整天一直接到大家恭喜我的電話
Hello?
哈囉？
No, he's not here. Yeah, this is his wife.
不，他不在家，我是他老婆
Yeah. Well, it came as quite a shock to me too!
是啊，我也被嚇了好大一跳
Well, I guess I should've known. He just kept making me watch Moulin Rouge.
嗯，我早就該猜到了 他總是強迫我看《紅磨坊》
Hang up! Hang up!
掛掉！掛掉！
And that was a great movie.
那是部好電影
I'm so gonna get back at Ross.
我一定會報復羅斯的
Oh, yeah, this'll show him. Here we go.
喔，是的，這會讓他好看 來吧
- What are you doing? - Oh, you'll see, my friend!
-你在做什麼呢？ -喔，你等著看吧，我的朋友！
I'm dead?
我死了？
And so young.
英年早逝
Posting that I died? That really isn't funny.
公告我死了？這一點都不好笑
Well, how you died was funny.
你怎麼死的比較好笑
Oh, please. Hit by a blimp?
拜託，被飛船撞死？
It kills over one Americans every year.
那每年都會殺死一個美國人的
Unbelievable. My classmates are gonna think I'm dead.
受不了，我同學們會以為我死了
My professors. My parents are gonna get phone calls!
我的教授，我父母會接到許多電話的
You're messing with people's feelings here.
你在玩弄大家的情感
You wanna talk about people's feelings? You should have heard how hurt..
你要談大家的情感是嗎？ 你應該要知道當我告訴史登教授…
Professor Stern was when I told him I wouldn't be able to go to Key West!
不能跟他一起去度假時，他有多受傷！
You've really crossed a line here. But that's okay.
你真的太過份了，但是沒關係
Because I'm on my way to buy some Photoshop software..
因為我要去買影像處理軟體
and a stack of gay porn.
和一疊的同志色情照片
That's right. Your coming-out is about to get real graphic!
沒錯，你的出櫃將會是圖文並茂了！
God, I wish Mike were here.
天啊，我真希望麥克在這裡
Okay, if Mike were here, what would the two of you be doing?
好了，如果麥克在這裡 你們要做什麼呢？
What are you, animals? It's 4:00 in the afternoon.
你們是動物嗎？現在才下午四點耶
I gotta call him. Just to talk to him. There's no harm in that.
我得打電話給他，只是跟他說說話 應該不會怎樣
That's how it starts. "I don't need to eat the cake, I'll just smell the icing.
事情都是那樣開始的 我不需要吃蛋糕，我只要聞一聞…
Why not just a little sliver?" Or, "Okay, just a slice or two."
那麼，一點點就好「或是 」好吧，一小片就好
The next thing you know, you're 210 pounds..
接下來一下子你就210磅了
and you get wedged in going down the tunnel slide!
而你連穿過門都會被卡住！
- That's not true, is it? - They had to cut me out..
-那不是真的吧 -他們得要破門才能…
with the Jaws of Life.
把我救出去
Phoebe, honey, I know this is hard.
菲比，親愛的，我知道這很難
But look, if you talk to him, then you're gonna want to see him.
但是如果你跟他說話 然後你就會想見他了
And if you see him, you're gonna wanna get back together.
而如果你見了他 你就會想跟他復合了
And I know that's not what you want.
我知道，那不是你想要的
All right, so give me your phone.
好了，把電話給我
Here.
拿去
- And now your cell. - Okay.
-還有你的手機 -好吧
There you go.
拿去
- This is your cell phone? - Yes.
-這是你的手機？ -是啊
This is your current cell phone?
這是你目前在用的手機？
Yes. It reminds me of a simpler time.
是的，它讓我想起簡單的往日
Phoebe? Where's your purse?
菲比？你的皮包呢？
- Hey! No! - No!
-嘿，不行 -不！
- Give it to me! - You can't have it!
-給我！ -不給你！
- Give it to me! - No!
-給我！ -不要！
- I'll go in there! - Oh, yeah.
-我會伸進去拿的！ -喔，是喔
- Phoebe, come here! - No!
-菲比，過來！ -不！
- Give it to me! - You're crazy!
-給我！ -你瘋了！
Damn you, Monica Geller hyphen Bing!
去你的，摩妮卡蓋勒—賓！
Don't even think of sneaking out and using a pay phone..
別想要偷跑出去打公用電話
because I am everywhere, baby!
因為我無所不在，寶貝！
Hey, look who's here. It's Joey. And he brought home a friend.
嘿，瞧瞧是誰來了，是喬伊 而且他帶新朋友來了
Emma's right here. You promised not to bring girls home in the middle of the day!
艾□在這裡，你答應不會在白天 帶女生回來的
No, no, no, it's not a girl. It's..
不、不、不，不是女生，是…
a brand-new Huggsy!
全新的哈吉！
Oh! Oh, that's so great! Now Emma has two Huggsies!
喔！這真是太棒了！ 現在艾□有兩個哈吉了
No, no. Oh, no. No, Emma has one Huggsy.
不、不，喔不 不，艾□只有一個哈吉
The new Huggsy.
新的哈吉
The other Huggsy, I don't know, I guess I'll just take him back.
另外那個哈吉，我不知道 我想我就把他拿回去好了
You know what? When I was a little girl, I had a little pink pony named Cotton.
你知道嗎？當我還是小女孩的時候 我有一隻粉紅色的小馬，叫小棉花
Oh, I loved her so much. I took her everywhere. I would braid her tail..
喔，我好愛她，去哪我都帶著她 我會梳她的尾巴…
Make the transfer!
快點移交吧！
Should I be concerned that a button fell off the old Huggsy and I can't find it?
舊哈吉身上有個鈕扣不見了，我找不到 有沒有關係？
No, don't worry about it. I swallowed that years ago. Hey!
不，不用擔心 很多年前被我吞下去了，嘿！
Oh, what? I don't think she likes the new Huggsy.
喔，怎麼了？我想她不喜歡新哈吉
- But he's the same. - I think she wants the old one back.
-但他是一樣的啊 -我想她要舊的哈吉
- Yeah, but he's the same. - Joey, come on.
-是喔，但他們一模一樣啊 -喬伊，拿來
But he's the same!
根本是一樣的嘛！
You're not the same.
你不一樣啦
You know, it's a lot less surprising to do that..
你這樣嚇不到我…
after I've buzzed you into the building.
因為是我按開樓下的門讓你進來的
So, Phoebe, why are there men's shoes by the door?
菲比，為什麼門邊有男人的鞋子呢？
Those are my shoes.
那是我的鞋子
Well, when you get over this breakup, we need to go shopping.
嗯，當你復元之後，我們一定要去血拼
Look, Monica, I really appreciate you checking in on me.
聽著，摩妮卡 我真的很感激你這樣關心我
- But I'm actually feeling a lot better. - You are?
-但是我已經覺得好多了 -真的？
Yeah, I just kind of want to be alone right now.
是的，我只是有點想自己獨處
- Who's that? - I ordered Chinese food.
-是誰啊？ -我叫了中餐外送
What are the chances?!
真是太巧了
One billion Chinese people, and they send Mike!
在十億的中國人當中 他們竟然派麥克來！
- What are you doing here? - Phoebe called me.
-你來這裡做什麼呢？ -菲比打電話給我
- Phoebe! - I'm sorry. I broke down.
-菲比！ -我很抱歉，我受不了
I wanted to see him.
我想要見他
Well, not on my watch.
在我的監視之下不准
Damn it, Phoebe, how did you even call him?
該死的，菲比 你是怎麼打電話給他的？
There's a speakerphone on the base unit.
電話主機有免持聽筒功能
Base unit. Think, Monica, think!
主機，用腦啊，摩妮卡，用用腦！
- Can I come in? - No! No.
-我可以進來嗎？ -不可以，不可以
Phoebe, isn't seeing Mike exactly what you wanted me to stop you from doing?
菲比，你不是要我阻止你 跟麥克見面嗎？
- Look, if I want to see Phoebe, and she.. - This doesn't concern you!
-聽著，如果我想見菲比，而她… -這不關你的事！
Sorry. I guess I was thrown off by the mention of my name.
對不起，我只是聽到有人提到我的名字
Look, guys, you can't do this.
聽著，你們不能這樣做
It's gonna make getting over each other harder.
這會使事情更複雜的
Not if nothing happens. Why can't we just hang out as friends?
如果什麼事都沒發生就不會 我們不能當朋友嗎？
Sure. If you're just gonna hang out as friends, then maybe I'll join you.
當然可以，如果你們只是朋友 那我也可以加入你們
You know, I'm your friend and Mike's friend.
你知道的，我是你的朋友 也是麥克的朋友
Sit down.
坐下吧
Make room for your friend.
讓個位置給你們的朋友
- So how have you been? - I've been pretty good.
-你過得好不好？ -我還挺不錯的
- You look really beautiful. - Thanks. You look good too.
-你真的很美 -謝謝，你看起來也不錯
No, no, no. This is dangerous territory. Keep it clean.
不對，這太危險了，放乾淨點
So how's the piano playing going?
那鋼琴演奏還好嗎？
Actually, I've been playing a lot of love songs lately.
事實上，我最近彈了許多情歌
- I've missed you. - I've missed you too.
-我一直很想你 -我也是
You know, on the way over here, I saw this drunk guy throw up.
在我要過來這裡的路上 我看到一個酒鬼吐了一地
And then a pigeon ate it.
然後一隻鴿子還去吃
Hey. Ross.
嘿，羅斯
Look, I just wanted to apologize.
聽著，我只是想過來跟你道歉
Don't tell me you actually made those gay pictures of me.
別告訴我你真的在做我的同志照
Check this out.
瞧瞧這個
So that's what I'd look like if I worked out.
所以如果我有健身，看起來就會是這樣
And was being serviced by a policeman.
而且還有警察先生為我服務
You're not gonna actually send these out, are you?
你不是真的要貼出這些照片吧？
Actually, I don't need to, because your little "Ross is dead" joke didn't work.
事實上，我沒有必要 因為「羅斯死了」的笑話根本沒用
Okay? There were no responses.
好嗎？根本就沒有人回應
Nobody posted anything, nobody called my parents, so the joke is on you.
沒有人張貼任何東西 沒有人打電話給我父母，你才好笑
Nobody called, nobody wrote anything, nobody cares that I'm dead.
沒有人來電，沒有人寫什麼 沒有人在乎我死了
Oh, my God.
喔，我的天
- Nobody cares that I'm dead? - Oh, come on, you know that's not true.
-沒有人在乎我死了嗎？ -喔，別這樣，你知道不是那樣的
What are you talking about? You get 60 responses..
你在說什麼呢？你有六十個回覆
just for coming out of the closet.
只不過是因為出櫃而已
I didn't get one response, and I'm dead!
而我死了，卻連一個回覆都沒有！
Well, the gay community is a lot more vocal than the dead community.
嗯，同志社團比死人社團還要活躍
I can't believe this. Not even my geology lab partner. And I carried that guy!
我不敢相信，連我地質學伴都沒有回覆 以前都是我罩他的！
Look, let's think about this, okay?
聽著，我們不要再多想了，好嗎？
You think people are gonna disturb your family at this tragic time?
你認為大家會想要在 這悲傷的時刻打擾你的家人嗎？
That people are gonna post condolences on a website?
有人會在網站上張貼哀悼辭嗎？
This isn't about people not caring.
不是說大家不在乎
This is about people not having a decent outlet for their grief.
而是那並非適合的抒發悲情的管道
- You're right. There isn't a decent outlet. - Right.
-你說的沒錯，那不是適合的管道 -沒錯
I'm sure if you had a funeral or memorial service, tons of people would come.
我確定如果你有舉辦追悼會 一定會有很多人來的
Exactly!
沒錯！
Ross, what are you doing?
羅斯，你要幹嘛？
You're having a memorial service for yourself?
你要幫自己辦追悼會？
No, that would be stupid. You're having it for me.
不，那會太離譜了，你要幫我辦
- Ross, don't press send. Don't press.. - No, too late. Too late. It's sent.
-羅斯，不要寄出，不要寄… -不，太遲了，太遲了，寄出了
Sorry, so is that picture of you and the policeman.
對不起，還有你 跟警察先生的照片也寄了
That's all right. I'm tan, limber..
沒關係，我曬的很黑又很健壯
And it looks like I talked my way out of that ticket.
看起來好像是我在求他不要開罰單
The surgery was not a success. And then you say:
手術失敗後，你說：
"What are we gonna do, Drake?"
「我們該怎麼辦，德克？」
Come in.
進來
I'm trying to put Emma down for a nap. Have you seen Huggsy?
我剛要哄艾□睡一下 你有看到哈吉嗎？
Original or crappy?
原版的還是爛的？
- Original. - No. Sorry. Haven't seen him.
-原版的 -沒有，抱歉，沒有看到
Then what's that big lump under your covers?
那你床上突起來的是什麼？
- It's Monica, okay? - That's not Monica!
-是摩妮卡，好嗎？ -那不是摩妮卡！
All right, fine! It's original Huggsy!
好啦，沒關係！是原版的哈吉！
I know Emma wants him, but he's mine and I need him.
我知道艾□要他 但他是我的，而我需要他
She's being unreasonable.
她真是不講道理
Joey, there is a reason that Emma loves that stupid penguin so much!
喬伊，艾□愛那個蠢企鵝是有原因的！
Oh, don't cover its ears!
喔，不要摀住他的耳朵！
It's because it reminds her of her Uncle Joey.
他讓她想起她的喬伊叔叔
- It does? - Yeah.
-真的？ -是的
And I think she really likes him because he smells like you.
而我認為她很喜歡他 是因為他聞起來有你的味道
And she.. She loves that.
而她很喜歡那味道的
Go figure.
誰知道呢
And she's comforted by him because she loves her Uncle Joey so much.
她很喜歡他是因為 她是那麼愛她的喬伊叔叔
- Really? She loves me? - Oh, yeah.
-真的？她愛我？ -喔，是的
But you know what? If you need Huggsy, don't worry.
但是你知道嗎？如果你需要哈吉 沒關係
Emma will totally understand. I won't, but whatever.
艾□會諒解的，我不會 但是那又如何呢
Okay, wait a minute, Rach. I mean, if..
好的，等等，瑞秋 我是說如果…
If Huggsy means that much to Emma, then..
如果艾□那麼喜歡哈吉，那麼…
Well, she can have him.
嗯，就給她吧
Oh, sweet, I knew Uncle Joey would step up.
喔，親愛的，我就知道喬伊叔叔最好了
- Look, Emma. Look who's back. - No, forget it! Forget it! I can't do it!
-瞧，艾□，瞧瞧是誰回來了 -不，算了！算了！我做不到！
Are you..? You're gonna take Huggsy away from a little child?
你…你要把哈吉從一個小孩手上搶走？
How do you think I got him in the first place?
要不然你認為我當初怎麼拿到哈吉的？
And then it just gobbled up that puke. I mean..
然後他就將吐出來的東西 狼吞虎嚥吃下去，我是說…
That was one gross pigeon.
那真是只噁心的鴿子
Oh, man. Why didn't I ask Joey to keep us apart?
天啊，我為什麼不是 請喬伊幫我們分開呢？
You throw a meatball in the hallway, we'd be doing it like rabbits right now.
只要在門外丟塊肉 現在我們就在床上打滾了
All right, you two. I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
好了，你們兩個，我要去上廁所
I don't want anything going on while I'm gone.
我不希望在我離開時 發生什麼事
Here's a few things you can discuss:
有幾件事你們可以討論
Mucus, fungus, and the idea of me and Ross doing it.
黏液、菌類 還有我跟羅斯如何把玩這些東西
I've missed you so much.
我真的好想你
I won't ask you to get back together. I know we want different things, but..
我不會要求你復合 我知道我們要的是不同的東西，但…
- Just to be with you one more night. - I want that too.
-只要跟你再共度一晚就好 -我也想要
- But is that gonna make it too hard? - It can't be any harder than this.
-但是那會使事情更困難嗎？ -再也不會比現在更困難了
I mean, if I had known the last time I saw you would be the last time, I..
如果我知道上一次見到你 就是最後一次，我…
I would have stopped to memorize your face, the way you moved.
我一定會努力記住你的臉 你的行動
Everything about you.
你的一舉一動
If I had known the last time I kissed you would be the last time..
如果我知道上次親吻你 就是最後一次…
I never would have stopped.
我就不會停下來
Kiss him, you fool!
親啊，你這個傻瓜！
- What? - Didn't you hear that speech?
-什麼？ -你沒有聽到他說什麼嗎？
If you don't kiss him, then I will.
如果你不親他，讓我來
I missed you so much.
我好想你
- I knew you'd be here! - Crap.
-我就知道你在這裡！ -媽的
- Who is this? - My friend Manny.
-他是誰？ -我朋友曼尼
I asked him to keep me away from you.
我請他看好我，遠離你
- Hey, that's what I'm doing for Phoebe. - Well, you're not doing a very good job.
-嘿，我也在幫菲比做同樣的事 -那你根本沒做好你的工作
- Excuse me? - What's with the kissing?
-什麼？ -親吻是怎麼回事呢？
Hey, at least I knew where my guy was.
嘿，至少我也在現場哪
Yeah, thank God you were here to oversee all the kissing.
是啊，感謝上帝 你在這裡監看他們親吻
- You didn't hear the speech. - I've heard the speech.
-你沒有聽到他說的話 -我聽到了
If he knew it was gonna be the last time..
如果他知道那是最後一次…
Hey, it was very moving. You're just heartless!
嘿，那很令人感動的 你真是沒心肝！
- You're weak! - You're weird!
-你太軟弱了！ -你太奇怪了！
Your pants are undone.
你褲子拉鏈沒拉
Where'd they go?
他們呢？
- Damn it. - Well, we blew it.
-該死的 -我們搞砸了
I blame myself.
我只能怪我自己
And I blame you too.
而我也只能怪你
It's been an hour, and not one of my classmates has shown up?
已經一個小時了 而我同學竟然一個都沒來？
I tell you, when I actually die, some people are gonna get seriously haunted.
我告訴你，要是我真的死了 有些人一定會被鬼纏死的
There you go. Someone came.
來了，有人來了
Okay. Okay. I'm gonna go hide.
好了，好了，我要去躲起來了
This is so exciting. My first mourner!
真是緊張，我第一個追悼者！
Hi. Glad you could come.
嗨，很高興你能夠來
- Please come in. - Hi. You're Chandler Bing, right?
-請進 -嗨，你是錢德賓嗎？
- I'm Tom Gordon. I was in your class. - Oh, yes. Yes, let me take your coat.
-我是湯姆高登，是你班上的同學 -喔，是的，是的，讓我幫你拿外套
Thanks. I'm so sorry about Ross, it's..
謝謝，很難過聽到羅斯的事，真是…
No, at least he died doing what he loved.
沒關係，至少他死時正在做喜歡的事
Watching blimps.
看飛船
- Who is it? - You know some guy, Tom Gordon?
-那是誰？ -你認識一個叫湯姆高登的嗎？
I don't remember him.
我不記得他了
But then again, I touched so many lives.
但是，我啟發過太多人了
So did you know Ross well?
那你跟羅斯很熟嗎？
Actually, I barely knew him. I came because I heard Chandler's news.
事實上我不太認識他 我來是因為聽到錢德的事
Do you know if he's seeing anyone?
你知道他有在跟誰交往嗎？
- Yes, he is. Me. - What? You mean..?
-是的，他有，就是我 -什麼？你是說…
Can I ask you a personal question? How do you shave your beard so close?
我可以問你一個私人問題嗎？ 你是怎麼將鬍子刮得這麼乾淨的？
Okay, Tommy! That's enough mourning for you.
好了，湯姆，你哀悼得夠了
Here we go Bye-bye. All right.
走吧，再見，好了
- Hey, listen. Call me. - Okay.
-嘿，聽著，打電話給我 -好的
- I'm dead and no one cares? - I look like a man?
-我死了還沒有人在乎？ -我看起來像男人嗎？
Please, one ridiculous problem at a time.
拜託，一次一個荒謬的問題就好
This isn't ridiculous. Look around, no one's here.
這並不荒謬，瞧瞧四周 根本沒有人來
You gave them one day's notice. Not everyone checks the website every day.
你才通知他們一天而已 又不是每個人天天都上網
And Monica, it's probably the way you stand!
還有摩妮卡，或許是你的站像！
I guess you're right. Still, somebody must have seen it.
我猜你說的對 但是，總該要有人看到啊
I went to that school for four years and I didn't have an impact on anyone?
我讀那所學校四年了 而我竟然沒有影響到任何人？
Well, that's not true. You had an impact on me.
嗯，不是那樣的 你有影響到我
I mean, it's 15 years later and we're still best friends.
我是說，已經十五年了 而我們依然是最要好的朋友
Doesn't that count for something?
那不算是什麼嗎？
Oh, great, more party boys for Chandler.
太好了，更多狂野男孩來找錢德了
I'm sure it's somebody for you. Now go hide.
我敢說一定是來看你的，去躲起來
Hi. I'm here for Ross Geller's memorial service.
嗨，我來參加羅斯蓋勒的追悼會
- Kori? Kori Weston? - Yeah.
-可芮？可芮薇絲頓？ -是的
- You look amazing. - And you are?
-你看起來真棒 -你是誰呢？
Chandler. Chandler Bing. And I'm not gay. I'm not gay at all.
錢德，錢德賓 而且我不是同志，我一點都不是
You are married, though.
但是你已經結婚了
Don't listen to him. He's in a really bad mood.
別聽他說，他只是心情很差
I can't believe that Ross is gone. It is just so sad.
我不敢相信羅斯已經走了 真是難過
I didn't know Ross and you were so close.
我不知道羅斯跟你很熟
Oh, we weren't. But we had one class together. He was such a great guy.
喔，並沒有，但是我們一起上過一堂課 他是個很棒的人
And he talked so passionately about science.
而且他總是很熱情地討論科學
- I always remembered him. - I'm sure that would mean a lot to him.
-我一直記得他 -我確定這對他的意義深遠
And if heaven has a door..
而且如果天堂有一扇門
I'm sure he's pressing his ear up against it and listening intently.
我敢說他一定耳朵貼著門仔細在聽
I thought so many times about calling him and asking him out.
我好多次都想打電話約他出去
I guess I really missed my chance.
我想我真的再也沒有機會了
No, you didn't!
不，你還有機會！
I'm still alive!
我還活著！
Who did we bury?
那我們埋葬的是誰？
Kori, I know this is a big surprise for you.
可芮，我知道這件事讓你很驚訝
It's a long story. But the things you just said really made my day.
說來話長，但是你剛說的話 讓我這一天變得很美好
The fact that you're here means more to me..
你的到來真是對我意義重大
than if this room were filled with people.
比房間都充滿了人還要好
You sick freak! Who does that?
你這變態的怪物！誰會做這種事？
I can't believe I had a crush on you.
我不敢相信我喜歡過你
Did you hear that?
你們有聽到嗎？
Kori Weston had a crush on me!
可芮薇絲頓喜歡過我！
No, Mom, I am not dead.
沒啦，媽，我沒死
I know it's not something to kid about.
我知道這是不可以開玩笑的
It was just a practical joke between Chandler and me, but it's over, okay?
這只是我跟錢德在玩的惡作劇 已經結束了，好嗎？
Actually, no. Even if I had died, you would not be left childless.
事實上不會的，即使我死了 你也不會沒有孩子
Monica?
摩妮卡不算嗎？